import type { ExamData } from "../../exam-data";

export const examData: ExamData = {
  title: "Piston Engine General Handling- Propellers-2",
  questions: [
    {
      "id": 1,
      "question": "What is the preferred direction for aircraft parking prior to start-up?",
      "options": [
        "Tail into wind",
        "Nose into wind",
        "1st engine to be started on windward side",
        "Facing towards the duty runway threshold to enable easy taxi-out"
      ],
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "question": "Prior to starting a piston aero-engine (in-line inverted) and after ensuring that the ignition is “OFF”, which check may have to be carried out?",
      "options": [
        "Check that the pilot’s flying licence is still in-date",
        "No further checks are necessary",
        "Obtain start-up permission from the Tower",
        "Carry out a check for engine hydraulicing"
      ],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "question": "When an engine starts up and the starter key is released, to what position does the key return?",
      "options": [
        "“OFF”",
        "“ON”",
        "“BOOSTER”",
        "“BOTH”"
      ],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "question": "Immediately an engine has started up, what is the first instrument reading to be checked?",
      "options": [
        "Oil pressure",
        "Battery volts",
        "Gyro erection",
        "Vacuum"
      ],
      "answer": 0
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "question": "What would be the likely effect of prolonged running with a weak mixture?",
      "options": [
        "Overheating",
        "Failure to come up to correct running temperature",
        "Carburettor icing",
        "High oil pressure"
      ],
      "answer": 0
    },
    {
      "id": 6,
      "question": "Should over-priming cause a fire to start in the engine’s carburettor during starting, what is the best immediate action?",
      "options": [
        "Evacuate the aircraft and make a “flash” call to the airport fire services",
        "Shut down the engine. The fire will extinguish itself",
        "Keep the engine turning on the starter motor and select “idle cut-off”. The fire should be drawn through the engine",
        "Select weak mixture on the mixture control and rapidly increase rpm"
      ],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "id": 7,
      "question": "When is the “Reference rpm” of an engine established?",
      "options": [
        "Before the first flight of the day",
        "During engine warm-up",
        "By the engine’s manufacturer during “Type Testing”",
        "When the engine is first installed in an aircraft"
      ],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "id": 8,
      "question": "When is “Static Boost” noted?",
      "options": [
        "Before engine start",
        "Just after engine start, while warming up",
        "It is permanently marked on the boost gauge",
        "It must be calculated from the airfield QNH"
      ],
      "answer": 0
    },
    {
      "id": 9,
      "question": "At what rpm is a magneto “dead cut” check carried out?",
      "options": [
        "At ground warm-up rpm",
        "At reference rpm",
        "At take-off rpm",
        "During the “Mag. drop” check"
      ],
      "answer": 0
    },
    {
      "id": 10,
      "question": "If, during a “Mag. drop” check the engine cuts, what action must be taken?",
      "options": [
        "Immediately switch to “Both” and recheck",
        "A grounding wire has broken and not earthing the primary circuit",
        "The engine must be stopped",
        "Decrease rpm to idle for no more than 1 minute. Reselect reference rpm and recheck"
      ],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "id": 11,
      "question": "If, during a “Mag. drop” check there is no drop in rpm, what is the most likely cause?",
      "options": [
        "A really good ignition system",
        "One of the switches being seized in the open circuit position",
        "One of the switches being seized in the closed circuit position",
        "The plug leads from that magneto have not been connected"
      ],
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "id": 12,
      "question": "What are the main reasons to exercise a propeller from fine to coarse pitch after warm-up?",
      "options": [
        "In order that a pilot may practise propeller control technique before take-off",
        "To pre-set the feathering signal before take-off, in case of an emergency",
        "To check that a full range of control is available at take-off boost",
        "To replace the cold oil in the pitch change mechanism and check rpm control"
      ],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "id": 13,
      "question": "At what mixture and carb. heat setting is a take-off normally carried out?",
      "options": [
        "Fully weak and carb. heat fully off",
        "Fully rich and carb. heat fully on",
        "Fully rich and carb. heat fully off",
        "Fully weak and carb. heat fully off"
      ],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "id": 14,
      "question": "Why, when climbing, is the engine temperature monitored carefully?",
      "options": [
        "A low temperature will be the only sign that pre-ignition is occurring",
        "Decreasing air density will reduce the engine cooling system’s efficiency",
        "A low engine temperature can give rise to poor atomization of fuel, and thus adversely affect Specific Fuel Consumption",
        "Use of high power at relatively low speed can allow engine temperature to creep up"
      ],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "id": 15,
      "question": "When cruising in a fixed-pitch propeller equipped aircraft, what, from the list below, would be the symptoms of carburettor icing?",
      "options": [
        "2, 3 and 5",
        "1, 2 and 7",
        "4, 5, 6 and 7",
        "3, 4, 5 and 7"
      ],
      "answer": 0
    },
    {
      "id": 16,
      "question": "What is the main danger from using a weak mixture at a high power setting?",
      "options": [
        "Low cylinder head temperature",
        "Low fuel pressure",
        "Pre-ignition",
        "Detonation"
      ],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "id": 17,
      "question": "What are the most likely effects on an engine of a low power, high speed descent?",
      "options": [
        "Engine overspeeding and consequent damage",
        "Engine overcooling and carburettor icing",
        "Engine overheating and oil cooler coring",
        "High oil temperature and piston ring gumming up"
      ],
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "id": 18,
      "question": "What problem is prevented by the use of the correct running down procedure?",
      "options": [
        "Spark plug fouling",
        "Oil cooler coring",
        "Very high rate of piston ring wear",
        "Over high temperatures on next start-up"
      ],
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "id": 19,
      "question": "What is the correct way to shut down an engine?",
      "options": [
        "Switch off both magnetos together",
        "Switch off the fuel booster pump",
        "Move the mixture control to ICO",
        "Feather the propeller when at idle rpm"
      ],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "id": 20,
      "question": "What are the two main symptoms of an excessively rich mixture?",
      "options": [
        "Loss of power and a drop in cylinder head temperature",
        "Gain in power and a drop in cylinder head temperature",
        "Loss of power and a rise in cylinder head temperature",
        "Gain in power and a rise in cylinder head temperature"
      ],
      "answer": 0
    }
  ]
}
